Willis, Ellen. Papers of Ellen Willis, 1941-2006: A Finding Aid
Papers of Ellen Willis, 1941-2006
- Series IV. TEACHING, SPEECHES, AND LECTURES, 1980-2006 (#8.9-10.42)
  - Subseries B. Speeches and lectures, 1980-2005 (#9.4-10.42)
    - "The Cultural Politics of Austerity," and "Free Speech and the Left," Union of Democratic Intellectuals conference, January 15-16, 1993, 10.4.
    - "Warhol, the Velvets, and the Deadpan Stance," Duke University, January 23, 1993, 10.5.
    - Re: manhating, Socialist Scholars conference, April 1993; version published as "Villains and Victims: 'Sexual Correctness' and the Repression of Feminism" in Salmagundi (Spring 1994), 10.6.
    - "The Cultural Legacy of the '60s," Wisconsin State Historical Society, April 29, 1993, 10.7.
    - "Return of the Repressed: Feminism and Freud," CUNY, October 22, 1993, 10.8.
    - "Feminism and the Politics of Reviewing" panel, Women's Review of Books conference, November 7, 1993, 10.9.
    - Response to Kathleen Hall Jamieson paper re: media representation of women, University of Pennsylvania, April 1, 1994, 10.10.
    - "The Unfinished Business of Democracy," Socialist Scholars conference, April 2-3, 1994, 10.11.
    - Re: "the new puritanism," Salmagundi conference, May 6, 1994, 10.12.
    - "Cultural Radicalism," TELOS conference, December 4, 1994, 10.13.
    - "The Future of Democracy," Socialist Scholars conference, April 7, 1995: includes transcript, 10.14.
    - "The Paradox of Rocklit," Symposium on Rockutopia, Vienna, Austria, April 28, 1995, 10.15.
    - Flyers for events, 1995-2005., 10.16.
      See also #F+D.1.
    - "The West and Politics," Society for the Interdisciplinary Study of Social Imagery conference, March 23, 1996, 10.17.
    - "Two Cheers for Utopia," Socialist Scholars conference, April 12, 1996, 10.18.
    - Response to Julianne Pidduck paper on gendered violence and representation, NYU American Studies colloquium, April 25, 1996, 10.19.
    - "Moralism and TV," Pleasures of Television conference, CUNY, May 10, 1996, 10.20.
    - "Passionate Intensity: The Cultural Unconscious in Contemporary Politics," NYU Gallatin School graduate seminar, October 15, 1996, 10.21.
    - "Living a Radical Life" panel, Dissent/NYU, October 23, 1996, 10.22.
    - "After the Media Event: Politics, Culture and the Social Text Affair," NYU, October 30, 1996: includes partial transcript, 10.23.
    - "The Crowd" panel, Stars Don't Stand Still in the Sky: Music Myth conference, Feruary 14, 1997, 10.24.
    - "Feminism and Ms. Jones: the Ironic Legacy of Thomas-Hill," University of Southern Colorado, March 13, 1997, 10.25.
    - "The Frontier and Free Market Utopianism," Society for the Interdisciplinary Study of Social Imagery conference, March 15, 1997, 10.26.
    - "Postmodernism: Radical or Reactionary?" panel, Socialist Scholars conference, March 29, 1997, 10.27.
    - "Public Intellectuals and Institutions," Public Intellectuals and the Future of Graduate Study conference, University of Chicago, June 11, 1997, 10.28.
    - "Reich and Feminism," Wilhelm Reich centennial, Belgrade, Yugoslavia, September 9, 1997, 10.29.
    - "Art, Politics, and Cultural Journalism," National Arts Journalism Program, October 24, 1997, 10.30.
    - Re: Bill Clinton sex scandal, 1997-2000, 10.31.
    - "The Left and Clinton" panel, Socialist Scholars conference, April 10, 1999, 10.32.
    - Re: free speech, 1990s, 10.33.
    - Re: intellectuals and activism, 1990s, 10.34.
    - Re: journalism and the arts, 1990s, 10.35.
    - "Economics, Culture and Class Politics," DC 37 [New York City public employee union], March 13, 2000, 10.36.
    - "Journalism and Cultural Studies" panel, International Crossroads Conference on Cultural S tudies, June 22, 2000, 10.37.
    - Re: utopia, October 2001, 10.38.
    - Re: Ralph Nader's 2000 presidential campaign, ca.2001, 10.39.
    - "Sex and American Politics" seminar lectures, ca.2004, 10.40.
    - "Is Abortion Important?," February 2005, 10.41.
    - Re: September 11, 2001, 2005, 10.42.
- Series V. AUDIOVISUAL, PHOTOGRAPHS, AND OVERSIZED, 1993-2002 (T-373.1, Vt-179.1 - Vt-179.3, PD.1, FD.1-FD.2, F+D.1, OD.1)
  - Willis interview on "Second Opinion," radio program hosted by Erwin Knoll, editor of The Progressive, 1993: after the publication of No More Nice Girls., T-373.1.
    REQUEST AS T-373, reel 1.
  - "Public Intellectuals" panel discussion at NYU with Ellen Willis, Michael Ignatieff,; Russell Jacoby,; Roger Kimball, and Alan Wolfe, sponsored by the Cultural Reporting and Criticism Program and Lingua Franca, March 1, 2001., Vt-179.1-Vt-179.2.
    REQUEST AS Vt-179, reels 1 and 2.
  - Clips from an Annie Sprinkle live performance, n.d., Vt-179.3.
    REQUEST AS Vt-179, reel 3.
  - Ellen Willis with others (possible students), 2002, n.d., PD.1.
  - Published articles, Boston Review, 2002, FD.1.
  - Items removed from #1.9, 4.17, 7.16, FD.2.
  - Program removed from #10.16, F+D.1.
  - Galleys removed from #7.13, OD.1.
Additional catalog entries
The following catalog entries represent persons, organizations, and topics documented in this collection. An entry for each appears in the Harvard On Line Library Information System (HOLLIS) and other automated bibliographic databases. THIS IS NOT AN INDEX.
Authors
Aronowitz, Nona Willis, 1984-
Christgau, Robert
Marcus, Greil
Oppenheimer, Judy, 1942-
Rolling stone
Sprinkle, Annie, 1954-
The Village voice
Subjects
Audiotapes
Berkeley (Calif.)--Social life and customs--20th century
Cheetah
College teachers--New York (State)--New York
Diaries
Dylan, Bob, 1941-
Electronic records
Essays
Feminism--United States
Feminists--United States
Jewish women--United States
Journalists--United States
Love-letters
Manuscripts for publication
Mothers and daughters
New York (N.Y.)--Social life and customs--20th century
New York University--Faculty
Popular music--United States--History and criticism
Pornography--United States--Public opinion
Radicals--United States
Reich, Wilhelm, 1897-1957
Reporters and reporting--United States
Rock music--United States--History and criticism
San Francisco (Calif.)--Social life and customs--20th century
Speeches
Teenage girls--United States
Videotapes
Web sites
Women--Sexual behavior
Women journalists--United States
Women radicals--United States
Women's rights--United States